What if the South had won the War?
C.S.A.: The Confederate States of America is a war,
comedy, drama film directed by Kevin Willmott.
Through the eyes of a British "documentary", this film takes a satirically humorous, and sometimes
frightening, look at the history of an America where the South won the Civil War.
Confederate Family Dad, played by Greg Kirsch.
Sherman Hoyle, played by Rupert Pate.
Bobby, played by Ryan L. Carroll.
Jefferson Davis, played by Brian Paulette.
John Ambrose Fauntroy V, played by Larry Peterson.
Patricia Johnson, played by Evamarii Johnson.
C.S.A.: The Confederate States of America is a 2004 American
mockumentary film written and directed by Kevin Willmott.
It is an account of an alternate history, in which the Confederacy wins the American Civil War and establishes a new Confederate States of America that
incorporates the majority of the Western Hemisphere, including the former contiguous United States, the "Golden Circle", the Caribbean, and South America.
Primarily detailing significant political and cultural events of Confederate history from its founding until the early 2000s, this viewpoint
is used to satirize real issues and events, and to shed light on the continuing existence of racism against Black Americans.
The film premiered at the 2004 Sundance Film Festival, and was released
in the United States on February 15, 2006, by IFC Films.
It received positive reviews.
The film explores themes of civil war, slavery,
mockumentary, social satire, alternate history.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.